Kennedy, William; Papers mss132
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Ironweed, 1970; 1978-1982; 2003; Undated; 4; 1.26 cu. ft.
  The files document the evolution of the book from a short novel called The Lemon Weed about an alcoholic named Buddy, based upon an actual man Kennedy met and repeatedly interviewed during the 1960s. Of interest are photographs of men and women like Buddy in the streets and missions, taken by a photojournalist friend of Kennedy's and included in the first draft of The Lemon Weed for Subsistence Press.
  Please see Series 8, Ironweed (Film Version), for materials documenting the transition of the book to film.
  - Preface to The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - The Lemon Weed with Missing "Helen" Section, 1970 (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - The Lemon Weed Stories, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - First Draft of The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Misc. Pages from The Lemon Weed, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - The Lemon Weed: A Short Novel, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - First Draft for Subsistence Press with Images, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Copy of First Draft for Subsistence Press, No Images, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Incomplete Draft, Undated (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Author's Note to Self, "The Quest", 1978 (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 10)
  - Three Page One Rewrites, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (4-Ironweed), Folder 11)
  - Completed First Draft of The Lemon Weed, 1979 (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Original Manuscript, Pages 17-255, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Chapters IV and V for Howard Hausman, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - First Draft of Ironweed, Incomplete, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - First Draft with Edits, Incomplete, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Revised (Second) Draft, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Revised (Second) Draft with Edits, Undated (Box 2 (4-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Chapter VI Revisions, 1980 (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Edited Pages with Notes, 1981 (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Second Draft, Viking Press Copy, 1982 (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Incomplete Second Draft, Pages 124-255, Undated (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Master Copy of Second Draft, with Edits, Undated (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Carbon Copy Pages, Undated (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Final Draft with Typesetters Notes (Folder 1 of 2), Undated (Box 3 (4-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Final Draft with Typesetters Notes (Folder 2 of 2), Undated (Box 4 (4-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Galley Proofs, ca. 1982 (Oversized 4, Folder 1)
  - Notes and Pages Pulled for University at Albany Speech, October 29, 2003 (Box 4 (4-Ironweed), Folder 2)
- O Albany!: Improbable City of Political Wizards, Fearless Ethnics, Spectacular Aristocrats, Splendid Nobodies, and Underrated Scoundrels, 1953-2002; Undated; 5; 2.34 cu. ft.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  Published in 1983, William Kennedy's nonfiction work O Albany! is based upon a series of articles he wrote about the city for the Albany Times-Union in the early-mid 1960s, which garnered him a Pulitzer Prize nomination for journalism. The book looks at Albany neighborhoods, different ethnic and racial groups who settled within the city, landmarks and institutions, and key political leaders. The series includes manuscripts and draft copy, Kennedy's earlier newspaper features, research materials and notes. As all the materials span a significant amount of time, please note the overall dates for this series are not inclusive.
  - Unfinished Draft of "Albany: Worst County, Longest Run", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - One Draft of "Albany, Why Albany?", 1978 (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - Nine Drafts of "Arbor Hill", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - One Draft of "Being Irish", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Six Drafts of "Blacks", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - Documents Regarding "Blacks", 1963-1997 (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Blacks", 1990; 1997; 2000-2001; Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - Author Notes for "Blacks/Poverty", 1965-1966 (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Blacks/Poverty", 1965-1966; 1971; Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Eight Drafts of "Bonafettle", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 10)
  - Four Drafts of "The Blvd. of Bluest Dreams", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 11)
  - Copy of 1980 Census, 1988 (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 12)
  - Three Drafts of "Capitol Hill", Undated (Box 1 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 13)
  - Nine Drafts of "Central Avenue", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - Working Drafts for "The Changing Face of Albany", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - "The Changing Face of Albany" News Clips, 1964 (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - Working Draft of "Debts and Butterings", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts of "Delaware Avenue I", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - Nine Drafts of "Delaware Avenue II", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - One Draft of "The Democrats Convene", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - Nine Drafts of "Downtown", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - Eight Drafts of "Epilogue", Undated (Box 2 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Three Drafts of "Erastus" with Notes, Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - Two Incomplete Drafts of "Erastus", Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - Complete Master Copy of "Erastus", Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - Working Draft for "The Last Word/Erastus", 1983 (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Oversized Research on Ethnic Groups, 1966-1999 (Oversized 5, Folder 1-2)
  - News Clippings on Various Ethnic Groups, 1988; 1990; 1999 (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - Literature and Notes Regarding Germans, 1953; 1981-1982; 1990; Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - "Greeks" Personal Correspondence, 2002 (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - Eight Drafts of "Introduction", Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - News Clips Regarding "Sons of St. Patrick", 1963; 1987-1989; 1996; Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Documents Regarding Ireland and "The Irish", 1991-1992; 1994; 1997; Undated (Box 3 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 10)
  - News Clips Regarding "The Irish", 1963; 1976; 1981; 1990; Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - Draft of Article "South End Italians," Articles 1 and 2, Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - Six Drafts of "The Italians", Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - News Clips Regarding "Italians", 1981; 1992 (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Three Drafts of "Jews", Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - "South End Jews," Articles 1 and 3, Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - Research Documents Regarding "Jews", 1957-1982; Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - Author Notes Regarding "Jews", Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - News Clippings Regarding "Jews", 1963-1964; 1976; 1982 (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Six Drafts of "Legs", Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 10)
  - Five Drafts of "The Mall Also Rises", 1971 (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 11)
  - Three Drafts of "Nighttown", Undated (Box 4 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 12)
  - Seven Drafts of "North Albany", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - Two Drafts of "A Walk on the Waters of Gander Bay", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - Two Drafts of "The Absolutely Last Hurrah is Yet to Come", 1966 (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - Six Drafts of "Dan I", 1974 (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Five Drafts of "Dan II", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - One Draft of "Dan II/They Bury the Boss", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - One Draft of "O'Connell", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - One Draft of "Sidebar: O'Dwyer on O'Connell", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - Five Drafts of "The Positively Last Hurrah Has Yet to be Heard", 1974 (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Eight Drafts of "Pine Hills", Undated (Box 5 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 10)
  - Six Drafts of "Prohibition", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 1)
  - Six Drafts of "Pruyn Connection I", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 2)
  - Eight Drafts of "Pruyn Connection II", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 3)
  - Eight Drafts of "South Mall", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts and Master Copy of "South Mall", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 5)
  - Four Drafts of "Sports and Swells", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 6)
  - Theater, 1987 (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 7)
  - Eight Writings on the Trinity Institution, Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 8)
  - Trinity Institution December Schedule, Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 9)
  - Five Drafts of "Union Station", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 10)
  - Documents Covering "The War on Poverty", 1966 (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 11)
  - Four Drafts of "West End I", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 12)
  - Four Drafts of "West End II", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 13)
  - Four Drafts of "The Whorehouse Neighborhood", Undated (Box 6 (5-O Albany!: Improbable City of Politi), Folder 14)
- Charlie Malarkey Books, 1975-1998; 2001; Undated; 6; 1.03 cu. ft.
  This series contains materials related to two children's books that William Kennedy wrote with his son Brendan; Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, published in 1986, and Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, which appeared in print in 1993. The series features working and edited drafts, galleys, newspaper clippings, reviews, and press tour materials. There also are several folders of correspondence. The files document the difficulties Kennedy encountered in attempting to publish the first book, including many rejection letters from publishing houses beginning in 1975. Of additional interest is correspondence about illustrations, foreign editions, possible film deals, and letters and a book from children who enjoyed the stories.
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Rejection Letters, 1975-1984; Undated (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 1)
  - Four Working Drafts with Author Notes, 1981 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 2)
  - Five Edited Drafts, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 3)
  - Seven Drafts of Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, 1984 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 4)
  - Four Drafts of Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine, 1985-1986 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Illustration Correspondence and Information, 1985-1986; 1988; 2001; Undated (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 6)
  - Atlantic Press Monthly Materials, 1986 (Oversized 5, Folder 3)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Atlantic Press Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 7)
  - The Atlantic Monthly Press Book List, 1986-1987 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 8)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Correspondence for Foreign Editions, 1986-1987; 1989-1990; 1992 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 9)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Personal Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 10)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine News Clippings, Articles, Reviews, 1986-1988; 1990; Undated (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 11)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Publicity, 1986; 1990; 1993; 1997; Undated (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 12)
  - Bubblegum Trees Correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 13)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Film Project Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 14)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Sixteen Drafts with Notes, 1990-1991 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 15)
  - Junior Writer's Week Information and Correspondence, 1990-1994 (Box 1 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 16)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Fourteen Drafts, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 1)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Nine Drafts, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 2)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Thirteen Edited and Revised Drafts, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 3)
  - P.S. 16 Student Letters and Stories, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Related Materials, 1991; 1998; Undated (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Illustration Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 6)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Film Correspondence, 1991-1993 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 7)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose/Penguin Correspondence, 1991-1994; 1996 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 8)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Edited Pages, 1992 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 9)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Final Copy and Three Revised Drafts, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 10)
  - Galleys for Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, 1993 (Oversized 5, Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose New Choices Correspondence and Article Information, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 1)
  - Penguin Correspondence for Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 2)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Publicity Papers, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 3)
  - Chandler School Class Reaction Letters, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 4)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Book Cover, Undated (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 5)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Belly Button Machine Author's Note, Undated (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 6)
  - Charlie Malarkey and the Singing Moose Author Notes, Undated (Box 3 (6-Charlie Malarkey), Folder 7)
  - Book Made by Schoolchildren for Kennedy, Undated (Oversized 5, Folder 5)
- The Cotton Club, 1983-1986; 1988-1989; 1993; 1997; Undated; 7; 2.25 cu. ft.
  In the summer of 1983 William Kennedy accepted director Francis Ford Coppola's invitation to collaborate with him on a film script for The Cotton Club, a 1930s period drama built around the real Harlem night club in New York. He spent the remainder of that summer and the fall writing and editing, as the movie transitioned from the pre-production phase to principal photography. The film debuted in the United States in 1984. This series documents that intensive writing and re-writing effort with many working scripts, rehearsal scripts, shooting scripts, and editing scripts. In addition, there are production memos and notes, call sheets, publicity materials, reviews, correspondence, and a file about the movie premiere.
  - Revised Working Draft by Francis Ford Coppola Only, Undated (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1)
  - Rehearsal Draft, July 25 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 2)
  - Rehearsal Draft with Revised Pages and Editing, July 25 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3)
  - Chronology of Scenes, July 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 4)
  - Call Sheets, July-November 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - Call Sheets, August-November 1983 (Oversized 4, Folder 2)
  - Revised Rehearsal Draft, August 3 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Sunday Afternoon Draft, Master Copy with Editing, August 7 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Sunday Night Draft, August 7 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 8)
  - Estimating Draft, August 8 1983 (Box 1 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 9)
  - Estimating Draft with Bob Evans Letter and Comments, August 8 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1)
  - Monday Preview Draft, August 15 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 2)
  - Shooting Script (Preliminary), August 16 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3)
  - Shooting Script, Saturday Night Draft, August 21 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 4)
  - Shooting Script, August 22 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - Shooting Script, Sunday Night Draft, August 22 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Shooting Script, Master Copy, August 22 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Revised Shooting Script, Working Draft, September 26 1983 (Box 2 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 8)
  - Revised Shooting Script, September 26 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1)
  - Final Draft, October 5 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 2)
  - Revised Shooting Script, October 16 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3)
  - Revised Shooting Script, October 26 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 4)
  - Revised Shooting Script, November 14 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - Finale, November 18 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Final Script, Master Copy, November 28 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Final Script, November 28 1983 (Box 3 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 8)
  - Final Script Rewrites, November 28 1983 (Box 4 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1-2)
  - Final Script, December 8 1983 (Box 4 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3-4)
  - Cutting Script, Undated (Box 4 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - Looping Script, Undated (Box 4 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Dixie Scenes, Undated (Box 4 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Line Scripts, Undated (Box 5 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1-2)
  - Scripts by Reel Number, Undated (Box 5 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3-5)
  - Script Rewrites, Undated (Box 5 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Script Revisions, Undated (Box 5 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Script Revisions with Author Notes, Undated (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1)
  - Script Rewrites, Undated (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 2)
  - The Cotton Club Revue and Scene Synopsis, Undated (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3)
  - Production Memos, 1983 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 4)
  - Production Notes, 1983 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - Staff and Crew List, Cast List, 1983 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Draft of Club Handbill, 1983 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
  - Robert Duvall Tribute, 1983 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 8)
  - Publicity over Financing of The Cotton Club, 1983-1984 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 9)
  - Publicity for The Cotton Club, 1983-1986; 1997; Undated (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 10)
  - World Premiere of The Cotton Club, Invitation and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 11)
  - Reviews and Publicity, 1984 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 12)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp" Vanity Fair (Folder 1 of 3), 1984 (Box 6 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 13)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp" Vanity Fair (Folders 2 and 3 of 3), 1984 (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 1-2)
  - Foreign Publicity, 1985 (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 3)
  - Murder of Roy Radin Clips, 1988-1989 (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 4)
  - "The Cotton Club Stomp,"Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1993 (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 5)
  - The Cotton Club Memorabilia, Undated (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Undated (Box 7 (7-The Cotton Club), Folder 7)
- Ironweed (Film Version), 1981-1997; Undated; 8; 2.01 cu. ft.
  This series documents the transition of Ironweed from the 1983 award-winning novel to film in 1987. Like the book, the movie focuses on the character of Francis Phelan and his return to Albany during the Depression. William Kennedy wrote the script for the film which was directed by Hector Babenco and starred Jack Nicholson and Meryl Streep. It was filmed on location in Albany and the surrounding areas. The materials include many draft and edited scripts, publicity materials, information about casting and locations, call sheets, correspondence, reviews, and two paperback copies of the novel with notes used for script writing. Note the overall dates for the series are not inclusive.
  Please see Series 4, Ironweed, for materials related to the writing of the novel.
  - Climate Information, 1981; Undated (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Raw First Draft, August 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Scene Sequence with Author Edits, August 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Author Notes, August 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Dialogue Draft, Undated (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - First Computer Typed Draft, September 3 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Script with Author Edits, Undated (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Script with Author Edits, September 5 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Incomplete First Draft with Edits, September 5 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of First Draft Script, September 5 1985 (Box 1 (8-Ironweed), Folder 10)
  - Complete First Draft, September 5 1985 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Copy of Second Draft with Author Edits, October 14 1985 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Third Draft, October 19 1985 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of [October 21, 1985] Script, Undated (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - First Draft with Changes Done with Hector Babenco, October 21 1985; October 1986 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)
  - Second Draft with Author Edits, October 10 1986 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 6)
  - Copy of Second Draft Script, October 11 1986 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 7)
  - Copy of Second Draft with Author Edits, October 11 1986 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 8)
  - Copy of Second Draft Script, October 13 1986 (Box 2 (8-Ironweed), Folder 9)
  - Superseded Pages, October 16 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 1)
  - Edited Pages, October 24 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 2)
  - Copy of Second Drafts with Author Edits, October 25 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of Location Scenes, October 25 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 4)
  - Revised Pages, October 26 1986 (Box 3 (8-Ironweed), Folder 5)